Souray Seal

Address: AD-170, Salt Lake, Kolkata 700064 Tel: +919051232709 DOB: 10/09/1992

Email: souravseal1992@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a Digital Marketing professional with 2+ years of experience in Digital Marketing, SEO Optimization, Google Ads, Facebook Ads and Website Development.

I also hold experience in sales and marketing in the Telecommunications and Banking Sector.

I hold a BSc Economics Honors Degree from Symbiosis International University and a MBA from Xavier Institute of Management University with specializations in Marketing.

EDUCATION

Xavier Institute of Management XIM University Bhubaneswar, Orissa

Master of Business Administration

Symbiosis School of Economics 2011-2016 Symbiosis International University Pune, Maharashtra BSc Economics

St. James School. Kolkata, West Bengal 2009-2011 ICSE & ISC Science

Freelancing/Blogging (SEO Specialist)

Experience

Kuhipaat Communications and Technology Pvt Ltd

Meridian and Double Equator, Dubai (Media Planner)

ICICI Bank Wealth Management (Deputy Manager)

Neps Technologies Pvt Ltd (Assistant Manager)

Rajasthan Grameen Ajeevika Vikas Parishad (Young Professional)

ICICI Foundation for Inclusive Growth (Internship)

Access Development Services (Internship)

18/5/22-Current

01/03/2022-18/5/22

10/03/2021-01/01/2022

2/11/2020-3/3/2021

15/4/ 2019-25/2/2020

02 April 2018 – 01 June 2018

1/12/ 2015-1/6/2016-1/4/2021-1/10/2020

1

2017 - 2019

CAREER HISTORY

Kuhipaat Communications and Technology Pvt Ltd, Assam Client Servicing Executive

2022 May - Now

- Managing Current Business for Clients and Focusing on Client Acquisition.
- Working with US Based clients-Lake Music Oregon, OET and Transformation Possible.
- Working with India Based Clients iBrow, Protech
- To conduct On Page SEO Optimization for all Clients Web Pages regularly.
- To test website changes according to client feedback on a regular basis.
- Make regular updates for On-Page content for client's website.
- To coordinate between FrontEnd, Backend and Design Team in relation to Client Needs.
- Coordinate client's Email Marketing, Google Ads, and Facebook Ads.
- Conduct Protech Blog SEO Optimization using Rankmath
- Manage Social Media Marketing for iBrow Permanent Makeup
- Regular Website testing for all Clients
- Sales and Marketing to Clients
- Presentation and documentation of Internal Google Ads Packages for Investment

Projects Handled

Protech Group Blog Page SEO Optimization

- Background- Protech Group is a real estate developer in Assam aiming to build long lasting brand awareness and positive brand equity by generating more leads to their website through their blog page.
- Solution- The solution for Kuhipaat is to publish maximum number of blogs every month for their website. Channels used for SEO Optimization are Rankmath, Google Analytics and Google Trends. Google analytics Using Google trends one can find out the search volumes of the keywords to determine the focus keywords for the blog. A Rankmath Score of 84/100, indicates that SEO is normally optimized.
- Outcomes: Brand awareness is developed and positive brand loyalty is maintained. Proper content marketing and SEO can promote the brand as an authority in their field, which leads to brand trust and builds brand. Final step is to find out maximum blog/page visits using Google Analytics metrics. Planning the next blog topics according the metrics for the best title.

IBrow Online Permanent Makeup Services in India

- Background-- iBrow is an online permanent makeup company aiming to provide methodical, scientific
 training to those interested in building a career in permanent makeup. Managing their social media
 handles according to the latest trends in the permanent makeup space will lead to positive brand
 equity.
- Solution- Social media marketing to build brand awareness is followed using Instagram. Posts are
 made on their social media handle using themes from their website. The posts consists of a theme,
 post description and post headline. Aim is to update at least one post per week. Primary aim are to
 gain followers, avoid unfollows and to be relevant. A dedicated budget is maintained for all
 promotional posts.
- Outcomes- Using Google Analytics metrics we can determine which themes attract more visitors to convert more leads.

Oregon Elite Tennis Online Coaching Classes

- **Background** Oregon Elite Tennis is a community of players, coaches and parents who support each other for competitions at the intermediate and advance levels. The company aims to reach as many students as possible for promoting tournaments through their social media handles and subscribers.
- Solution- The way forward is to update the website regularly basis the feedback presented by the client. Feedback comprises of HTTPS security of the website, updated plans and packages, Font changes, using up to date images, HD video quality, perfecting the alignment and design. Regular on Page SEO optimization is the only fix to keep the website up and running. Regular website maintenance, SEO Audits and research are the solution.
- Outcomes- Deadlines are maintained for all website maintenance tasks. Proper content marketing and On-Page SEO can promote the website as an authority in their field, which leads to client trust and brand loyalty. Customer perception changes over time leading to credibility and trust around the OET programs.

Kuhipaat Communications Pvt Ltd Google Ads Services Packages

- Background- Kuhipaat Communications with their expertise in online Google Ad placements and organic SEO have packaged services for effective and economically viable marketing through their Google Ads Services Packages.
- **Solution** Google ads services packages are applicable for the entire online space designed for start-up projects in Google and online advertisements. Google ads services packages are targeted towards provide advertisements on desktop/laptop mobile/tablet and computer users with landing page creations option as well as email marketing and SMS services.
- Outcomes- The type and nature of Google Ad package differs from case to case. The right
 combination of Google advertisement service India parameter selection and Google ad strategy
 planning ensures the most efficient utilization of the advertisement fund. Kuhipaat has an experience
 in analysing media and keyword research that are unique in nature. Industry specific search terms are
 easily researched to get maximum value from the Google Ads Services Packages.

Meridian and Double Equator, Dubai Media Planner

2022 March - 2022 May

- Media Planner with <u>Google Ads</u> Search Certification .Knowhow on how to grow business with Google Ads Search.
- Experience working with Google Paid Ads.
- Understanding on how to deliver the right message with Google Text ads. Expertise on how to make ads search relevant with search ad extensions.
- Skills on how to reach valued customers through automated bidding for specific search audiences.
- Certified in Google on how to boost performance with SEO optimization and performance planner.
- Relevant <u>Facebook ads</u> experience for building and monitoring Facebook ad campaigns on Facebook
 Advertisement Digital Platform. Research on types of audiences to optimize campaign performance. Learnt
 competitor analysis through effective CPC strategies.
- Conducted <u>Campaigns on IPL</u> Facebook Audience and Search engine Optimization for IPL Keywords. Conducted IPL Player ranking index research. Learnt effective bidding strategies for quality IPL keywords.

ICICI Bank Wealth Management, Kolkata Wealth Manager

2021 March-2022 January

- Managing HNI client portfolio to grow financial base
- IRDAI Certified and AMFI Certified
- Controlling financial inflows and outflows for managed client base.
- Cross selling the bank products across the managed client base.
- Building Client network for the Bank.
- Undergo continuous on job product training.

Neps Technologies Pvt Ltd Assistant Manager

2020 Novemeber-2022 March

- Sales Operations in Telecommunications Industry
- Social Media Marketing Management
- Sales CRM Management
- Building Dealer Network

Rajasthan Grameen Ajeevika Vikas Parishad Young Professional

2019 April-2020 February

- Block Project Manager
- District Manager (Institution Building Community Mobilization Financial Inclusion)
- Monitoring and Evaluation
- Conduct Impact Assessment Studies
- Capturing Success Stories
- Implementing Projects in Potential Areas

Freelancing/Blogging/SEO

2015-16-2019-20

- Writing Blogs
- Academic Content Writing
- SEO Optimization
- Webpage Content Creation
- Product Reviews

Academic Projects/Achievements and Internships

- Completed Training on 'Digital Marketing' at Eazycoach Educational Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata 2017
- Completed training on 'Social Survey on Child Labour at Child Rights and You (CRY), Kolkata, in 2014
- Completed Immersion Course on 'Quantitative and Qualitative Data Analytics Using R 'at Xavier University Bhubaneshwar, 2018
- Completed Immersion Course on 'Dairy Business' at Xavier University Bhubaneshwar, 2018

Positions of Responsibility

- Treasurer, Skill City Gaming Committee for batch 2017-19 at Xavier University, Bhubaneshwar
- President, SHG/VO/CLF Audit Committee for RGAVP 2019-20, District, Dholpur, Rajasthan.

Extracurricular Achievements

- Completed Live Project on 'Conducting Customer Perception study', Eicher Tractors
- Member of XIMB-XUB Toastmasters Club for Xavier School of Rural Management for the year 2017-18
- Held Quarter Finalist position, in the 11th Inter School Tennis Tournament for Boys, Indian Tennis Academy, 2007